In addition to setting the rows and columns of the grid,
بالإضافة إلى ضبط الصفوف والأعمدة في الشبكة،
CSS grid allows you to explicitly place items within that grid.
تتيح شبكة CSS إمكانية وضع العناصر في مواضع محددة وظاهرة في الشبكة.
To understand this, we'll use the grid area concept to define
لفهم الأمر، نستخدم مفهوم منطقة الشبكة لتعريف
the space across rows and columns that elements take up.
المساحة التي تحتلها العناصر عبر الصفوف والأعمدة.
The grid area CSS property is actually a shorthand property for grid row start,
خاصية منطقة الشبكة في CSS هي في الواقع خاصية تختزل معلومات بداية صف الشبكة
grid columns start, grid row end,
وبداية عمود الشبكة ونهاية صف الشبكة
and grid column end.
ونهاية عمود الشبكة.
But instead of using each of these,
فبدلًا من استخدام كل هذه المعلومات
we can actually just use named grid areas,
نستعيض عنها بمناطق الشبكة المسمّاة فحسب،
which I think our CSS grid is most powerful feature.
والتي أعتقد أنها أكثر ميزة فعالة في شبكة CSS.
That's where we're going to spend some time right now.
وهذا ما سنتحدث عنه الآن.
So name grid spaces allow you to develop and create an actual grid in your code with
تتيح تسمية مساحات الشبكة لنا تطوير وإنشاء شبكة فعلية في برمجيتنا باستخدام
names paces that can be added to the grid area property of individual items on that grid.
المساحات المسماة التي يمكن إضافتها إلى خاصية منطقة الشبكة لكل عنصر في الشبكة على حِدة.
Don't worry. I'm going to show you what this looks like in practice.
لا داعي للقلق، سأعرض أمثلة عملية لتوضيح الأمر.
But right now you can take a look,
ولكن أولًا، لنلق نظرة إلى هذا المثال
and you'll be familiar with our columns,
تعرفنا سابقًا على الأعمدة
and our rows, and our grid gap,
والصفوف وفراغ الشبكة،
and the new part here is the grid template area,
أما الجزء الجديد هنا فهو منطقة قالب الشبكة،
which is actually just laid out here using strength.
والذي وضع هنا باستخدام سلاسل برمجية
It's creating a grid, saying,
حيث تنشئ شبكة بوضع تعليمات تقول
there are two columns on the top,
أن هناك عمودان في الصف العلوي
two columns on the bottom row,
وعمودان في الصف السفلي
and then we could associate these with particular items in the grid.
بعد ذلك يمكننا ربطها بعناصر محددة في الشبكة.
Let's see what this looks like in action.
لنر كيف يتم ذلك بشكل عملي.